this video is brought to you by my book
which can be found on amazon or
foldableflight.com
links in the description below
in this video i'm going to teach you how
to fold three amazing paper airplanes
that all fly really far and they're all
relatively easy to fold now these two
you might recognize from existing videos
on my channel but this one is entirely
new to this video so at least check that
one out but really all three of these
are well worth a fold if you're
interested in learning how to fold the
hammerhead be sure to check out the
video i just posted to power up toys
today by clicking that card in the top
right corner with that out of the way
let me show you these three planes in
flight and then i'll teach you how to
fold them
[Music]
[Applause]
all you will need in order to fold
arrowhead is an eight and a half by
eleven or a a4 sheet of paper and we'll
begin by folding this right edge to the
left edge
and we'll go ahead and open that up and
we want to fold this top edge down
so that we're making a bar that's about
one inch long
or thick
and any approximation is good enough it
doesn't have to be precise we'll go
ahead and flip that back over and now
fold this into the center
and we'll do the same thing on the other
side
okay and your paper should look like
this and now we want to fold this whole
top section down like so
and fold this point back up to the top
like so
and now we'll go ahead and flip this
over
and i want to fold this top edge into
the center
and i'll do the same thing on this side
and i'm actually going to open up both
of those folds and now i want to fold
this edge to that crease
and i'll do the same thing on this side
and now i can fold both of those in like
so
and next we want to kind of pick up our
plane and you can see we've got this tab
behind here and a pocket and we want to
fit this point into that pocket and the
way we're going to do that is we're
going to kind of bend use your thumb to
push and bend this
point and you want to aim off center
if you aim in the middle you're very
likely to tear your pocket so aim off
center and just slide that nose right in
under that layer
and then let the plane kind of
self-correct as you feed those layers
inside and then you're going to want to
flip it over and kind of smooth this out
here to make sure your layers kind of
become a bit tidier not bubbling as much
and your plane should look like this and
we'll go ahead and just fold it in half
like so
now we're going to just fold the wings
so just fold this edge here to that edge
there
go ahead and do the other side
and there you go this is a finished
arrowhead be sure to angle your wings
upwards slightly and then also bend the
back edges of your wings up just a
little bit giving it up elevator which
is going to help keep your plane from
diving
the f-15 jet was designed by joshua
doors of the origami aviator so be sure
to click that card in the top right
corner to find more amazing paper
airplane content
in order to fold this f-15 jet you're
going to need both an eight and a half
by 11 inch sheet of paper and a pair of
scissors so with that we will begin by
folding this right edge to the left edge
and while we have it like this we can go
ahead and fold this top edge here to our
folded edge
making a nice triangle
and i'll flip it over and do the same
thing on this side
and i'll go ahead and open my plane up
into this orientation
next step is just to fold this top point
all the way to the bottom
and now we want to go ahead and fold
this top point back up and i'll show you
right where you want to crease basically
reveal these top triangles and you want
your crease to be right across the
bottom of those
and try to make sure that your creases
line up on this side as well
and you can press it all flat
i'm actually going to go ahead and
unfold back into this orientation
and next you want to fold this here to
the center crease
but you're not going to crease all the
way down the sheet of paper you just
want to
crease right up until you hit
you can see this diagonal crease right
there that's where you want to stop your
crease so you can see
i just creased to that point i'll do the
same thing on this side
just creasing to this point right there
and i'll open that back up
and now i'll fold down on that crease
back up on this crease and we are ready
for the next step which is definitely
the trickiest step here basically what
we want to perform what's called a
swivel fold and we're going to fold in
using this existing crease
and you can see it creates this pocket
in the paper and basically we want to
stick our finger into this pocket and
force it all the way open
right to that point there that my left
hand is pointing at
and then you can kind of flatten and fan
out this side of the paper
kind of like so
and just flatten it
and you're kind of your limit is going
to be how far can you pull it that way
it's going to catch right on that corner
there and then you can flatten
i'll do the same thing on this side so
again i'm just pulling this all the way
closed and that is going to mean i have
a pocket here that i'm
kind of forcing open you can see it it
doesn't start all the way open right
there i want it to open up all the way
to that point
and then i can start to kind of flatten
it
and i'm looking to flatten and create my
edge going straight to that point
so there we go
and i'll go ahead and flatten this side
as well
your plane should look like this
the next step is to go ahead and uh
open this up and pull
that inner layer out
and then fold on this existing crease to
put it onto that side there we're just
going to open this up and you grab that
layer out
and fold it in the opposite direction
and we'll fold this in like so
and this side in like so
and now i want to fold this bottom edge
here and i'm going to go ahead and fold
it and then i'll explain to you exactly
how i decided how far i wanted to fold
it up so you can see that's the crease i
made
what i wanted to do is i landed this
edge here right on the intersection of
this edge
and this vertical crease that exists
right there so that is my reference
point i'm folding this edge to land
right there
and that is my crease i'll do the same
thing on the other side
okay
and your plane should look like this
next we just want to reverse these
creases we just made i'm going to
actually rotate the plane 100
yeah 180 degrees as i do that and i want
to kind of smooth out this section this
thick section is going to be the hard
part to reverse and just start bending
it in the opposite direction under those
other layers
because we want that to be the bottom
layer of all this
we'll do the same thing on the other
side here
this is the part you're gonna have to
focus on right there
really work on that
and the rest will follow pretty easily
so there you go
and now i'm going to go ahead and fold
this here
to land on our center crease and you can
see i want to land it on this inner
crease in such a way that the crease
goes right to this point where this flap
catches on
this edge here
so i'll fold
something like that
and then i'll do the same thing on the
other side as well
okay
so your plane should look like this
the next step sorry i'm just trying to
work out this little kink in there okay
the next step is we're going to be
closing the whole model
but as we do that you can see i have a
tab here on one of these on both you can
decide to use either one i want to
basically slide this tab
behind
into this pocket on the other side and
that's going to lock our plane together
so if i just
as i close
tuck that in does that make sense i'm
closing it up like so
and you can see i'm folded in half but
now my plane wants to lock together
and while we have the plane in this
orientation now we're going to line up
our back corners here make sure those
are nicely lined and just hold
our plane like this and grab our
scissors because we're going to now cut
those really cool fins
that are on this plane basically i just
want to start about an inch from this
back corner
and cut
diagonally in like so
you can see that's what an inch and a
half to a little less than two inches
maybe and then i cut straight in from
the edge to that point
there you go get rid of those triangles
that fall and now we are ready to go
ahead and fold the wings of our plane so
we're just folding this here to the
bottom edge this front section kind of
guides the angle we're creasing on and
you can let this portion of the wing go
past the edge
and i'll do the same thing on the other
side
and our last step now is to fold our
fins the rear fins up and what we want
to do is create a crease from this point
here to the back edge that runs parallel
to this edge of the paper
and that's just going to be an
estimation
but something like that and i'll flip it
over and fold this side to match my
other side so i'm just trying to land
this on that corner there
and now i can open this all up and set
my fins to be vertical my wings angled
slightly upwards in kind of a y shape
and this is going to fly so well for you
this is an f-15
beautiful jet
good luck flying
all you will need in order to fold
dagger is an eight and a half by 11 inch
sheet of paper and we will begin by
folding this right edge to the left edge
and while we have the paper in this
orientation with this as our folded edge
we want to fold from this corner here to
that corner and that's a little bit
tricky but if you pull
this top edge until it kind of catches
on that top corner that's going to give
you an anchor where then you can kind of
swivel this whole thing
and aim it right towards that corner
and you can kind of just work those into
place and then crease
the full length of the fold like so
and we'll go ahead and do the same thing
on the other side this time just trying
to match our first fold even if we
didn't get that perfectly the first time
okay and now we'll go ahead and open the
paper up and you can
open one side up and leave the other
side down and we want to fold the
portion that goes across the center
crease back across the center crease
and
we want to land the new crease we're
making
on the center crease
like so we'll do the same thing on the
other side laying that down and then
folding back across
and your plane should look like this
next we're going to note this point here
where this edge
and this edge intersect that center
point our center crease
and we're going to fold this down on
this side and we want the horizontal
crease that we're going to make to go
straight through that intersection here
on this side but we're not going to
crease all the way yet we just want to
tack that point where this flap is
meeting our top edge and then we're
going to flip over
and make sure that our center crease on
this layer lines up with our center
crease on that layer that's going to
make sure our plane stays symmetrical
and then you can kind of pull that into
place
make sure everything's lined up
and
crease all the way across like so
and then we'll go ahead and actually
just open it back up into this
orientation here and you can see this is
an easy crease for us to kind of pinch
and grab and we're going to pull it down
and we want to land this corner right
here
on this edge
land our center crease on this center
crease and this corner on that edge
those are your three references
as you
make this next crease
like so
and we'll go ahead and open it back up
into this position and i'm going to flip
this
to the other side
what i want to do now is fold this edge
here to our center crease
and i'm only going to crease until i get
to this line so you can see as i pull
this
and kind of get it lined up i'm going to
start
just right here and
crease towards the top edge because i
don't want to go past
this point when i'm creasing
and then i'll flip this to the other
side flip this to the other side and do
the same thing here this edge to the
center
again i'm not going to crease all the
way down this one
i'm just creasing to this point right
here
and then i'll open that up
and position our plane like this
now i'm going to fold on this bottom
crease fold up on the top crease
and
now i'll push this to the other side
and i want to do what's called the
swivel fold now this is a pretty tricky
fold we're going to use the existing
crease we have here to pull this in
and you can see it's going to make a
pocket here and really there are two
sides of this pocket one here and one
there and this one's going to be the one
that wants to be open but we need to
use our thumb use a finger to force this
side open and you want it to catch
all the way to this point right here
so you can kind of see
that point is the intersection of this
edge and that edge that's where we're
opening the whole thing up to
and then you can swivel it open like so
so that you get a tight
pull
between this point and that point
and then you can crease that and that
dictates kind of what the angle change
from here to here is going to be
and you can just crease the full wing
out like so
and now we'll go ahead and push this
back to this side and do the same thing
on the other side
so i'm folding in here this side wants
to be open but actually i want this side
of the pocket to be the one that opens
up
and then i pull out like so
swiveling outwards until i can crease
that
and crease that
okay and now i'll push this back to the
other side
the next crease i'm going to make is by
pulling this
over here and i want to basically make a
crease
that lands on this edge so i'm basically
pulling the paper just until i see that
edge
and i make my crease right on top of it
so you can see
my edge is landing on the outer edge of
the profile of the plane there and now
i'm going to go ahead and fold back
across the center and land my next
crease
on the center crease
and i'll fold back one more time and
land this crease on that outer edge
like so
and i will open this up and leave it in
this position
now i'm going to go ahead and do all
those things on the other side as well
so i'm folding this
landing my crease on this outer edge
folding back across the center landing
my crease on the center
and then fold back landing this crease
on that outer edge
and you can see now
we've basically positioned ourselves so
that this can all
fit within the profile of our plane
but what we want to do is we're going to
be tucking some layers into these inner
pockets
and so we actually want to we don't want
to reverse this crease here but the one
after it we want that
to fold in the opposite direction
and then this outer one is also going to
need to fold in the opposite direction
and now i can kind of
open this pocket up
fold the whole thing in like so and tuck
these layers
into
the plane
and you can see i have a portion that
sticks out i'm going to gently open the
other side and let that cross the center
into the other side
now i'm going to open this up and i want
to reverse this crease here
and reverse this crease here
so you can see there's my kind of crease
pattern valley here mountain there
and i'm going to fold in
and tuck these into this side
like so
and now this portion wants to cross the
center i'm going to allow it to go into
that right side pocket
and our plane should now be really nice
and tidy like this you can see we've got
these loose flaps still you can tuck one
flap into this little pocket and one
flap into this little pocket
and this is going to hold our plane
together very nicely
all the layers should be locked together
now
and now we're going to go ahead and fold
the plane in half
you will have to make a new crease here
towards the top because of those
portions that crossed our center crease
and we now want to fold the wings and
what we're going to do to fold the wings
is we're going to fold this edge here to
this edge and this is a little tough too
because it's a thick bunch of paper and
a narrow crease
and you basically this wide portion of
the wing is going to go way past the
bottom edge but you want to land this
long narrow section right on
the bottom edge of your paper if you can
this is very hard to do without getting
some wrinkles in your plane
it's just thick and narrow and that's
really okay you're not going to get a
perfectly clean fold but
do as well as you can of course
your plane's still going to fly well
even if this isn't perfect so once i've
done that i'll go ahead and flip it over
and fold the other side to match
try really hard to line up these corners
here
that's of course if you've maintained
symmetry up to this point i know that's
a challenge sometimes
and we will put our plane down in this
orientation
kind of smooth this all out
and now we just want to fold some outer
fins and we're going to fold them
parallel to the center crease
and right through this intersection of
this layer and this layer so i'll fold
one
just kind of estimating as best i can
what is parallel to that center crease
and once you do one side
you'll want to hold your plane in this
position flip it over and fold the other
side to hit again land the corner on the
corner to make sure that your fins are
the same size
and orientation
so there you go this is a finished
dagger which
is just such a striking plane i mean
it's got these really cool aesthetic to
it and it's gonna fly really well for
you too so i wish you the best of luck
as you go flying